<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>summary on Harsha Kokel</title>
    <link>https://harshakokel.com/tags/summary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in summary on Harsha Kokel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Original-Theme is licensed with the Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 16:40:08 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harshakokel.com/tags/summary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> The 6 Types of Neuro-Symbolic Systems</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/neurosymbolic-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/neurosymbolic-systems/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Henry Kautz, in his Robert S. Engelmore Memorial Lecture at AAAI 2020^, talked about the past and present of AI and highlighted that the future of AI is in the combination of the Neural and Symbolic approaches, alluding to the famous and heated AI debate between Prof. Gary Marcus and Prof. Yoshua Benjio. In this regard, he brings forth a taxonomy of Neuro-Symbolic Systems that I aim to elaborate upon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools for Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/causal-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/causal-tools/</guid>
      <description>There is enough motivation now showing the necessity of learning models that have a correct causal structure. The famous &amp;ldquo;Correlation is not causation&amp;rdquo; quote should ring a bell. Although the research on learning causal structure from observed data has not yet shown its potential. There are certain tasks from causal literature which can still be solved by just using observed data. Specifically, interventional and counterfactual queries can still be answered if we know the causal structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitted Q and Batch Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/batch-rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/batch-rl/</guid>
      <description>Terminologies Offline Planning Problem (MDP) We are given the full MDP model and the problem is solved using all the components of the MDP
Online Planning Problem (RL) We have limited knowledge of the MDP. We can discover it by interacting with the system
Model-based RL Approaches to solving Online planning problem (RL) by first estimating (when missing) or accessing the full MDP Model i.e. transition and reward function and then finding policy $\pi$ is called Model-based RL</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
