<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>summary on Harsha Kokel</title>
    <link>https://harshakokel.com/tags/summary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in summary on Harsha Kokel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Original-Theme is licensed with the Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 16:40:08 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harshakokel.com/tags/summary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> The 6 Types of Neuro-Symbolic Systems</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/neurosymbolic-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/neurosymbolic-systems/</guid>
      <description>I attended the AAAI 2020 conference in NY, and one of the most influencing talk in that conference (for me, of course!) was the address by Prof. Henry Kautz on &lt;a href=&#34;https://roc-hci.com/announcements/the-third-ai-summer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Third AI Summer&lt;/a&gt;. In that talk, he provided some taxonomy for the future Neural and Symbolic approaches. This article is my attempt to summarize that taxonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools for Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/causal-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/causal-tools/</guid>
      <description>I read the Book of Why last year and recently in the reading group at Starling lab we read the 7 Tools of causal inference by Prof. Pearl. I was a little taken by how much I have forgotten about causal inference. So I found the need to jolt down my understanding, so I can refer to it later. This article summarized my current understanding of the tools presented in the paper, based on the paper and the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitted Q and Batch Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/batch-rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/batch-rl/</guid>
      <description>Some pointers on Batch Reinforcement Learning and Fitted Q. These were gathered while working on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://harshakokel.com/pdf/ECMO-RL.pdf&#34;&gt;RL for healthcare&lt;/a&gt; project, as part of Advanced RL course by Prof. Sriraam Natarajan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
