<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SRL on Home</title>
    <link>https://harshakokel.com/tags/srl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SRL on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Original-Theme is licensed with the Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:40:08 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harshakokel.com/tags/srl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Relational Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/rrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/rrl/</guid>
      <description>Džeroski, Sašo, Luc De Raedt, and Kurt Driessens, Machine Learning 2001 The paper came before the goal-conditioned RL, Multi-task RL or Graph Neural Network literature. Major motivation of this paper is to learn a generalizable policy. Generalization in terms of varying number of objects in the domain (for example, in blocks-world number of blocks can change) or change in the goal state (for example, stack red block on blue block instead if green on yellow).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Relational Learning to Predict Primary Myocardial Infarction from Electronic Health Records</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/srl-for-myocardialinfarction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/srl-for-myocardialinfarction/</guid>
      <description>Jeremy C. Weiss, Sriraam Natarajan, Peggy L. Peissig, Catherine McCarty, and David Page, IAAI 2012 Myocardial Infarctions (generally known as heart attacks) causes one in three deaths in the United States and unsurprisingly have the most mysterious trajectory. It has been established that the prediction of future MIs is a challenging task and hence there have been extensive studies to identify and/or quantify the risk factors that contribute to MIs. Few common risk factors that have been identified are age, gender, blood pressure, low-density lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol, diabetes, obesity, inactivity, alcohol and smoking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BLOG: Relational Modeling with Unknown Objects</title>
      <link>https://harshakokel.com/posts/bayesian-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 16:40:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harshakokel.com/posts/bayesian-logic/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Logic (BLOG) by Milch et al. provides a language which help us model random functions and probabilistic properties of unknown objects. Going beyong Herbrand Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
